lomography.com 2019-04-07

# Privacy Policy · Lomography

At the Lomography, we believe our online visitors have the right to know our practices regarding data we may collect when you visit our web sites. The policies contained herein apply to your visit to the web sites operated by Lomography and affiliated entities. We sincerely guarantee taking the highest care in protecting the privacy of our customers! 

We invest in high-quality security and do our utmost to protect user privacy through the appropriate use of the latest security technology. We shall take appropriate security measures to prevent unauthorised access, disclosure, modification, or destruction of Data. 

In order to participate in activities on our websites, it will be necessary for you to provide us with some personally identifiable information. If you choose not to provide this information, you may not be able to participate in these activities. 

The Data is kept for the time stated in this document, and you can always request suspension or removal of your data. 

The data processing exclusively takes place according to the mandatory regulations of the Austrian Telecommunications Act (TKG 2003) and the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR, DSGVO). It takes place in the European Union, Switzerland, and the United States. The data processing in Switzerland and the United States is compliant with the Privacy Shield Framework. 

**Please read this privacy policy carefully** , as it informs you on the major aspects of the data processing on our web site and is integral part of our Terms and Conditions. We consider your continued use of our site and / or registration on it a freely given, specific, informed, and unambiguous agreement to the processing of personal data as described below. 

##  Contacting Us 

If you contact us through forms or directly by email, we store the data provided for six months for the purpose of processing the inquiry and follow-up questions. 

We will not pass on any individual user details (including your email address) for third party use unless we have your prior consent. 

##  Web Shop Data Collection 

For the purpose of an improved shopping experience and later execution of the contract, we as web shop operator collect the IP address assigned to you by your internet service provider, as well as name and postal address of the buyer. 

By placing your Order, you agree and understand that we may store, process and use data collected from your Order Form for the purposes of processing your Order. Please note that we may also share such data globally within the Lomography group of companies. 

All transactions are processed through 128-bit encryption. 

We work with other companies that help us provide products and services to you. For example we may provide your name, address, and telephone number to companies for the shipment of products to you, or to ensure that you benefit from special purchase discounts or terms. In addition, where you request online payment-handling services, some of the information you provide will be passed to payment providers to authorise for your purchase. 

Our payment providers are: 

Stripe Inc., 185 Berry Street, Suite 550, San Francisco, CA 94107, USA, compliant with the EU-US Privacy Shield Framework; privacy policy: <https://stripe.com/at/privacy>

PayPal; PayPal (Europe) S.à.r.l. & Cie. S.C.A., 22-24 Boulevard Royal, 2449 Luxembourg, Luxembourg; privacy policy: <https://www.paypal.com/cg/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full>

For the management of legal and fiscal aspects of our contractual relationships, we provide data to external professional legal and fiscal consultants to fulfil the requirements of the applicable laws or regulations, in particular, related to tax matters. 

The data provided is required for the fulfilment of contractual purposes or for the implementation of pre-contractual measures. Absent this data we cannot conclude contracts with you! 

If you cancel a shopping process, the data collected will be deleted immediately. If a contract has been concluded, all data collected from this contract will be stored according to tax regulations for seven years. Name, address, articles purchased, and date of purchase will be stored ten years for product responsibility. Data processing is according to legal requirements of § 96 Abs 3 TKG 2003 and Art 6 para 1 lit a (consent) and/or lit b (necessary for the performance of a contract), and/or lit c (legal obligation) of the EU-GDPR. 

##  Cookies, Analytics and Tracking Pixels 

###  What are Cookies? 

To remember you, our website and web shop will give you a cookie. Don’t worry, it’s safe! As it is common practice with almost all professional websites, this site uses cookies, which are tiny text files that are downloaded by your browser to your device to improve your experience. Cookies do not cause any damage on your device and do not contain viruses. Any use of cookies by us or third party service providers serves to identify users and remember their preferences. 

###  What are Tracking Pixels? 

We also use so-called tracking pixels. A tracking pixel is a miniature graphic that is embedded in web pages to enable a log file recording and a log file analysis through which a statistical analysis may be performed. Based on the embedded tracking pixels, we are able to determine if and when our site was opened, and which links were clicked on by you. Tracking pixels serve to analyse the flow of visitors on a website. 

###  The Cookies We Set 

We use cookies when you are logged in so that we can remember this fact. This prevents you from having to log in every single time you visit a new page. These cookies are typically removed or cleared when you log out to ensure that you can only access restricted features and areas when logged in. These cookies will usually be deleted when you log out however in some cases they may remain afterwards until you remove them. 

If you create an account with us we will use cookies for the management of the signup process and general administration. 

You can prevent the setting of cookies by adjusting the settings on your browser (see your browser help for how to do this). Be aware that disabling cookies will affect the functionality of this and many other websites that you visit. Disabling cookies will usually also result in disabling certain functionality and features of this site. Therefore it is recommended that you do not disable cookies. 

###  Third Party Cookies 

In some special cases we also use cookies provided by trusted third parties. The following section details which third party cookies you might encounter through this site. 

Several partners advertise on our behalf and affiliate tracking cookies simply allow us to see if our customers have come to the site through one of our partner sites so that we can credit them appropriately and where applicable allow our affiliate partners to provide any bonus that they may provide you for making a purchase. 

###  Third Party Analytics & Advertising Partners 

We use the following partners: 

Google Analytics, Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View CA 94043, USA, compliant with the EU-US Privacy Shield Framework. 

Google Analytics is the most widespread and trusted analytics solutions on the web for helping us to understand how you use the site and ways that we can improve your experience. Thanks to cookies, we track how long you spend on the site and the pages that you visit, so we can continue to produce engaging content. Traffic audiences may be created and linked with Google Adwords, which is a service showing search ads on top of organic search results on Google.com. This means that we might adjust advertising bids or messages to your past browsing behavior, if you happen to be looking for triggered search keywords. For more information, see Google’s privacy policy: <https://www.google.com/analytics/terms/us.html>, or their help center: <https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245>. You can prevent Analytics from tracking your behavior by downloading a specific browser extension, see more information here: <https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/181881>

Facebook Pixel, Facebook Inc., 1601 S. California Ave, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA, compliant with the EU-US Privacy Shield Framework. 

The Facebook Pixel is a code on our website that lets us measure and track the actions taken by you on our site. It can then help building advertising audiences thanks the actions tracked. 

We want our advertising experience to be as relevant and interesting as the other information you find on this social media. With this in mind, we use all of the information the Facebook pixel provides us to show our ads only to people who could be interested in our products, as well as to people who have recently viewed pages on our website. To read more about their services, please refer to their privacy policy: <https://www.facebook.com/policy.php>. To manage your advertising preferences, you can edit your Facebook account settings: [https://www.facebook.com/ads/preferences/?entry_product=education_page](https://www.facebook.com/ads/preferences/?entry_product%3Deducation_page)

Criteo Dynamic Retargeting, 32 Rue Blanche, 75009 Paris, France 

Criteo is among the most used partner for online advertising. Re-targeting technologies use your cookies and display advertisements based on your past browsing behavior. This enables us to show our advertisements to visitors who are interested in our products on partners' websites and apps. To read more and/or oppose to their services, please refer to their privacy policy: [https://www.criteo.com/privacy](https://www.criteo.com/privacy/)

###  Data of Cookies, Analytics and Tracking Pixels 

The collected data is transferred to the respective service provider in the European Union, Switzerland, or the United States, where it is stored and evaluated. The terms and conditions for carrying out data processing are subject to strict contractual obligations, in which the parties agree on data protection and information security requirements. Our service providers are only able to process data on our behalf and in accordance with our instructions. 

Your IP address will be collected for Google Analytics and Criteo Dynamic Retargeting in pseudonymous form, which is a non-precise information related to your geography and derived from the truncated IP address of your connection. It will be collected in order to serve you ads only for products and services available in your country, region or city. This makes only a rough geo-localisation possible. Your full IP addresses may only be used by Criteo for fraud detection purposes, sales attribution, and marketing reports with aggregated data. 

The Facebook Pixel collects your full IP address with each call-up of our site. However, any customer data you pass through the Facebook pixel is hashed locally on the browser before it goes to the Facebook servers for matching. This hashing process turns your data into short encrypted messages that cannot be tampered with. They use these hashes to match pixel events with people on Facebook. Then Facebook deletes all matched and unmatched hashes immediately after the matching process ends. They do not collect or store any personally identifiable information on their servers. The Facebook pixel uses secure https connection, so that any data transmitted from the browser will make it to their servers safely. 

Data processing is according to legal requirements of § 96 Abs 3 TKG 2003 and Art 6 para 1 lit a (consent) and/or lit f (legitimate interests) of the EU-GDPR. Our legitimate interests for the purposes of this regulation are improvement of our products, services and online presence. 

Web analysis user data will only be deleted upon request. Without any requests from you, we consider your continued use of our site as a consent for those technologies. 

##  Newsletter 

You may subscribe to subscribe to our newsletter on our website. We only need your email address and your consent to receiving our newsletter. If you subscribe to our newsletter, we will send you an email with a link to confirm your subscription. 

You may cancel the subscription to our newsletter at any point by sending your cancellation to [help@lomography.com](mailto:help@lomography.com). We will promptly delete your data regarding newsletter transmission. 

##  Data Protection Compliance for Recruitment 

We process submitted applications and other data in the field of employment for recruitment purposes only and we will not share it with anyone else. 

We delete this data six months after our vacancies are filled in accordance with the Equal Treatment Act (GlBG). We cannot estimate the exact time period until a vacancy is filled, but we will consider this period over when a candidate bindingly accepts our offer for the position for which we are considering you. When that period is over, we will either delete your data or inform you that we will keep it in our database for future roles. 

##  Email Communications 

If you create an account with us, we will email you occasionally with information or queries about your registration, your subscription account or postings, reminders, follow-ups on products, warnings, or copyright requests. We also send a reminder if you have items in your cart, but did not check out yet. 

If you do not want to receive e-mail from us, please visit the Email Preferences section of your User Profile and/or follow the instructions contained in the unwanted e-mail message. However, please note that in all cases you will continue to receive all system e-mails (e.g. those regarding forgotten user passwords) and legal notices (e.g. updates to our policies) from us. 

If you make a purchase through our website, we might use your email address to build custom targeted audiences on Facebook or send targeted newsletters for marketing campaigns that will only be relevant to you. You will not receive unsolicited marketing emails from this third party partner, and we will not share your email address with anyone else without your prior consent. The emails lists we pass to Facebook will be hashed to turn your data into short encrypted messages that cannot be tampered with. Facebook does not collect nor store any email information on their servers. 

If you do not want to receive marketing emails, please let us know and we will remove your information promptly. If you wish to opt-out from future advertising campaigns from us, please visit your Facebook account ads preferences: [https://www.facebook.com/ads/preferences/?entry_product=education_page](https://www.facebook.com/ads/preferences/?entry_product%3Deducation_page). 

##  Additional Data Collection and Processing 

Please also consider the following data collection, data processing and privacy respective policies of our service providers! 

Personal data you provide and/or publish through your community account will be stored until either you remove it, delete your account, or request removal by us. The collected data is forwarded to the server of our hosting service provider, where it is being stored: Hetzner Online GmbH, Industriestr. 25, 91710 Gunzenhausen, Germany 

Necessary backups of data is being stored at Amazon Web Services (AWS): <https://aws.amazon.com/de/contact-us/>; compliant with the EU-US Privacy Shield Framework 

We use the content delivery networks to distribute our services spatially relative to you and to provide high availability and high performance. Our content delivery networks are: 

KeyCDN; proinity LLC, Ruemikerstrasse 60, CH-8409 Winterthur, Switzerland; privacy policy: <https://www.keycdn.com/privacy>

Imgix; https://www.imgix.com/contact-us; privacy policy: <https://www.imgix.com/privacy>

Our fonts are provided by Hoefler & Co.; 611 Broadway, Room 725, New York, NY 10012-2608 USA; privacy policy: <https://www.typography.com/home/privacy.php>

The terms and conditions for hosting data processing, content delivery, and other services we use are subject to strict contractual obligations, in which the parties agree on data protection and information security requirements. Our service providers and content delivery networks are only able to process data on our behalf and in accordance with our instructions and are compliant with the EU-US Privacy Shield Framework. 

Postings on our web services are not private and may be published and edited at our discretion. Your postings are stored and published, as well as connected information, such as date, time, pseudonym, and assigned IP address. This storage of the IP address takes place for security reasons, in case someone violates the rights of third parties, or posts illegal content. Users are responsible for any personal data of third parties obtained, published or shared through our services and confirm that they have the third party’s consent. 

We will never release the name or other personal information about a Member without the permission of that Member other than as required by law, but reserves the right to distribute aggregated demographic information provided by Members. 

The exchange between us and the Member of information such as passwords or electronic mail may not be secure given the current state of the Internet. We encourage Members to change their passwords frequently! 

Personal data may be used for legal purposes, in court or in the stages leading to possible legal action arising from improper use of our services. We may be required to reveal collected data upon request of public authorities. 

For operation, error tracking and maintenance purposes, we may record system logs or IP addresses for the duration of the specific maintenance. 

We may offer social media sharing functionality on our site. The social media buttons (eg. twitter, facebook, tumblr, pinterest) on this site allow you to connect with your social network and other services in various ways. These are links to other services that do not compromise your privacy without your intervention. Please note that we have no influence on the extent of the data retrieved by these services if you follow these links or activate plugins by clicking on them. They will track and set cookies which may be used to enhance your profile on their site or contribute to the data they hold for various purposes outlined in their respective privacy policies. 

On our site, we use integrated components (embeds). With each call-up to one of our individual pages on which an embedded component is integrated, your browser is automatically prompted to download a display of the corresponding component. During display of the component, the provider of the component may gain knowledge of what specific sub-page of our website was visited and your IP address. 

We have integrated (embedded): 

YouTube; YouTube, LLC 901 Cherry Ave., San Bruno, CA 94066, USA; privacy policy: [https://www.youtube.com/static?template=privacy_guidelines](https://www.youtube.com/static?template%3Dprivacy_guidelines); opt-out: <https://support.google.com/ads/answer/2662922>

Vimeo; Vimeo, Inc., 555 West 18th Street, New York, New York 10011, USA; privacy policy: <https://vimeo.com/privacy>; opt-out: <https://vimeo.com/opt_out>

Soundcloud; SoundCloud Limited, Rheinsberger Str. 76/77, 10115 Berlin, Germany; privacy policy and opt-out: <https://soundcloud.com/pages/privacy>

Giphy; Giphy, 416 W. 13th Street, Suite 207, New York, NY 10014, USA; privacy policy and opt-out: <https://giphy.com/privacy>

Data processing is according to legal requirements of § 96 Abs 3 TKG 2003 and Art 6 para 1 lit a (consent), lit b (necessary for the performance of a contract), lit c (legal obligation), and/or lit f (legitimate interests) of the EU-GDPR. 

##  The Rights of Users 

Users have the right, at any time, to know whether their personal data has been stored and can consult us to learn about their contents and origin, to verify their accuracy or to ask for them to be supplemented, cancelled, updated or corrected, or for their transformation into anonymous format or to block any data held in violation of the law, as well as to oppose their treatment for any and all legitimate reasons. Requests should be sent to the data controller at the contact information set out below. 

If you suppose that our processing of your data violates applicable data protection laws, you may lodge a complaint with the competent supervisory authority. In the member states of the European Union, these are the national data protection authorities: <http://ec.europa.eu/justice/article-29/structure/data-protection-authorities/index_en.htm>

The EU-U.S. and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Frameworks were designed by the U.S. Department of Commerce and the European Commission and Swiss Administration to provide companies on both sides of the Atlantic with a mechanism to comply with data protection requirements when transferring personal data from the European Union and Switzerland to the United States in support of transatlantic commerce. You can find a list of compliant entities and information on dispute resolution here: <https://www.privacyshield.gov/list>

Our website does not support “Do Not Track” requests. 

##  Changes to this Privacy Policy 

Privacy policy may be due to changes. You will be notified about any changes to it! 

Lomography may amend this Privacy Policy from time to time, at its sole discretion. Use of information we collect now is subject to the Privacy Policy in effect at the time such information is used. If we make changes to the Privacy Policy, we will notify you so that you always consent to what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances if any, it is disclosed. 

##  How to Get into Touch with Us 

More details concerning the collection or processing of Personal Data may be requested from us at any time: 

Lomographische AG  
Kaiserstraße 34, 1070 Vienna, Austria  
Tel.:+43 1 89944 - 0 

##  About 

Place of jurisdiction and legal venue: Commercial Court of Vienna # 134784 m  
Registered under number 134784 m  
Member of the Austrian Federal Economic Chamber, Vienna  
Legal provisions applicable: Austrian law ([www.ris.bka.gv.at](http://www.ris.bka.gv.at/)), excluding its conflicts of law rules; In particular applicable is the Trade Regulation Act of 1994 (GewO 1994)  
Supervisory Authority: City Administration of Vienna  
 **This Privacy Policy is effective as of May 25, 2018.**
